const questions = [
  {
    question:
      "Which among the following Kavya of Sanskrit, deal with court intrigues & access to power of Chandragupta Maurya? ?",
    optionA: "Mrichhakatika",
    optionB: "Ritusamhara",
    optionC: "Kumarasambhava",
    optionD: "Mudrarakshahsa",
    correctOption: "optionD",
  },

  {
    question: "Which of the following statement is wrong? ?",
    optionA: " Sunga dynasty was founded by pushyamitra",
    optionB: " Ashoka the great Mauryan king died in 332 BC",
    optionC: "Ashoka invaded the kalinga in 261 BC",
    optionD: " Chandragupta Maurya earned the title of the Liberator.",
    correctOption: "optionB",
  },

  {
    question:
      " On which of the following systems of Hindu Philosophy , Shankaracharya wrote commentary in 9th century AD? ?",
    optionA: " Sankhya",
    optionB: "Vaisheshika",
    optionC: "Yoga",
    optionD: " Uttarmimansa",
    correctOption: "optionD",
  },

  {
    question:
      " Who was the first Indian ruler who had territory outside India?",
    optionA: "Ashoka",
    optionB: "Chandragupta Mauryar",
    optionC: " Kanishka",
    optionD: "Huvishka",
    correctOption: "optionC",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which king started the organization of Kumbh fair at Allahabad??",
    optionA: "Akabar",
    optionB: " Dhruvasena Ii",
    optionC: "Narshimhvarman",
    optionD: " Harshavardhana",
    correctOption: "optionD",
  },

  {
    question: " Where were the hymns of Rigveda composed? ?",
    optionA: " Punjab",
    optionB: "Gujarat",
    optionC: "Rajasthan",
    optionD: "Uttar Pradesh",
    correctOption: "optionA",
  },

  {
    question: " Which empire lasted the longest among the following ?",
    optionA: "The Palas",
    optionB: "The Pratiharas",
    optionC: " The Rashtrakutas",
    optionD: "The Senas",
    correctOption: "optionC",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was the last Hindu emperor of northern India?",
    optionA: "Harsha",
    optionB: " Pulakesin II",
    optionC: " Rajyavardhana",
    optionD: "Skandagupta",
    correctOption: "optionA",
  },

  {
    question:
      "On which river the Rig Veda and Indus Civilizations were based ?",
    optionA: "Narmada",
    optionB: "Ganga",
    optionC: "Godavari",
    optionD: "Saraswati",
    correctOption: "optionD",
  },

  {
    question: `"What led to the end of Indus Valley Civilization?`,
    optionA: "Invasion of Aryans",
    optionB: "Recurrent Floods",
    optionC: "Earthquakes",
    optionD: "All the above",
    correctOption: "optionD",
  },

  {
    question: " Which among the following is not correct ?",
    optionA: "The capital of pandyas was Madurai",
    optionB: " The capital of Cheras was Vanchi",
    optionC: " Capital of the Videha Kingdom – Mithila",
    optionD: "Capital of Gahadwal Dynasty – Kannauj",
    correctOption: "optionC",
  },

  {
    question: "Who was the main male God worshipped by Indus people ?",
    optionA: " Lord Vishnu",
    optionB: "Vishnu",
    optionC: "Brahma",
    optionD: "Indra",
    correctOption: "optionA",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which among the following was the royal emblem of Chera Kingdom?",
    optionA: "Tiger",
    optionB: "Bow",
    optionC: "Fish",
    optionD: "Carp",
    correctOption: "optionB",
  },

  {
    question:
      "handragupta Maurya under the able guidance of Kautilya uprooted which of the following Kings ?",
    optionA: "Shishunaga",
    optionB: "Kalasoka",
    optionC: "Mahapadma Nanda",
    optionD: "Dhanananda",
    correctOption: "optionD",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Buddha established an order of monks and nuns which was known as ?",
    optionA: " Sangha",
    optionB: "Jana",
    optionC: "Vidhatha",
    optionD: " Kirat",
    correctOption: "optionA",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which Harappan site in below had direct sea trade links with Mesopotamia ?",
    optionA: "Kot Diji",
    optionB: "Dholavira",
    optionC: "Lothal",
    optionD: "Ropar",
    correctOption: "optionC",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The Asirgadh Inscription in Nimar district of Madhya Pradesh describes the victory of which of the following kings?",
    optionA: "Sarvavarmana",
    optionB: " Advaita Varmana",
    optionC: "Grahavarmana",
    optionD: "Avanti Varmana",
    correctOption: "optionA",
  },

  {
    question: "The Rig Veda consists of how many hymns ?",
    optionA: "1000",
    optionB: "1024",
    optionC: "1028",
    optionD: "1030",
    correctOption: "optionC",
  },

  {
    question: "Which of the following age is also known as copper age ?",
    optionA: "Paleolithic age",
    optionB: " Neolithic age",
    optionC: "Mesolithic age",
    optionD: "Chalcolithic age",
    correctOption: "optionD",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which among the following major rock edicts of Ashoka are in Kharosthi script ?",
    optionA: " Mansehra and Sahbazgarhi",
    optionB: "Sanchi",
    optionC: "Sarnath",
    optionD: "Bairut",
    correctOption: "optionA",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which among the following veda has been described as “Braham Veda ?",
    optionA: "Rigveda",
    optionB: "Samaveda",
    optionC: "Yajurveda",
    optionD: "Atharavaveda",
    correctOption: "optionD",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who was the earliest known Chola King who conquered Sri Lanka and ruled it  ?",
    optionA: "Karikala",
    optionB: "Elara",
    optionC: "Udiyangera",
    optionD: "Nedunjelian",
    correctOption: "optionB",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which of the following temples from the Gupta per?Which of the following temples from the Gupta period is entirely made up of Bricks?",
    optionA: "Dasavatar Temple",
    optionB: " Bhitargaon temple",
    optionC: "Shiva Temple of Bhumara",
    optionD: "Shiva Temple of Koh",
    correctOption: "optionB",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Jejakabhukti was the ancient name of which of the following places ?",
    optionA: "Ujjain",
    optionB: "Mathura",
    optionC: "Bundelkhand",
    optionD: "Rajasthan",
    correctOption: "optionC",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Who was the ruler of the kingdom between the rivers Jhelum and Chenab?",
    optionA: " Alexander the Great",
    optionB: "Darius III",
    optionC: "King Porus",
    optionD: " Chandragupta Maurya",
    correctOption: "optionC",
  },
];

let shuffledQuestions = []; //empty array to hold shuffled selected questions out of all available questions

function handleQuestions() {
  //function to shuffle and push 10 questions to shuffledQuestions array
  //app would be dealing with 10questions per session
  while (shuffledQuestions.length <= 9) {
    const random = questions[Math.floor(Math.random() * questions.length)];
    if (!shuffledQuestions.includes(random)) {
      shuffledQuestions.push(random);
    }
  }
}

let questionNumber = 1; //holds the current question number
let playerScore = 0; //holds the player score
let wrongAttempt = 0; //amount of wrong answers picked by player
let indexNumber = 0; //will be used in displaying next question

// function for displaying next question in the array to dom
//also handles displaying players and quiz information to dom
function NextQuestion(index) {
  handleQuestions();
  const currentQuestion = shuffledQuestions[index];
  document.getElementById("question-number").innerHTML = questionNumber;
  document.getElementById("player-score").innerHTML = playerScore;
  document.getElementById("display-question").innerHTML =
    currentQuestion.question;
  document.getElementById("option-one-label").innerHTML =
    currentQuestion.optionA;
  document.getElementById("option-two-label").innerHTML =
    currentQuestion.optionB;
  document.getElementById("option-three-label").innerHTML =
    currentQuestion.optionC;
  document.getElementById("option-four-label").innerHTML =
    currentQuestion.optionD;
}

function checkForAnswer() {
  const currentQuestion = shuffledQuestions[indexNumber]; //gets current Question
  const currentQuestionAnswer = currentQuestion.correctOption; //gets current Question's answer
  const options = document.getElementsByName("option"); //gets all elements in dom with name of 'option' (in this the radio inputs)
  let correctOption = null;

  options.forEach((option) => {
    if (option.value === currentQuestionAnswer) {
      //get's correct's radio input with correct answer
      correctOption = option.labels[0].id;
    }
  });

  //checking to make sure a radio input has been checked or an option being chosen
  if (
    options[0].checked === false &&
    options[1].checked === false &&
    options[2].checked === false &&
    options[3].checked == false
  ) {
    document.getElementById("option-modal").style.display = "flex";
  }

  //checking if checked radio button is same as answer
  options.forEach((option) => {
    if (option.checked === true && option.value === currentQuestionAnswer) {
      document.getElementById(correctOption).style.backgroundColor = "green";
      playerScore++; //adding to player's score
      indexNumber++; //adding 1 to index so has to display next question..
      //set to delay question number till when next question loads
      setTimeout(() => {
        questionNumber++;
      }, 1000);
    } else if (option.checked && option.value !== currentQuestionAnswer) {
      const wrongLabelId = option.labels[0].id;
      document.getElementById(wrongLabelId).style.backgroundColor = "red";
      document.getElementById(correctOption).style.backgroundColor = "green";
      wrongAttempt++; //adds 1 to wrong attempts
      indexNumber++;
      //set to delay question number till when next question loads
      setTimeout(() => {
        questionNumber++;
      }, 1000);
    }
  });
}

//called when the next button is called
function handleNextQuestion() {
  checkForAnswer(); //check if player picked right or wrong option
  unCheckRadioButtons();
  //delays next question displaying for a second just for some effects so questions don't rush in on player
  setTimeout(() => {
    if (indexNumber <= 9) {
      //displays next question as long as index number isn't greater than 9, remember index number starts from 0, so index 9 is question 10
      NextQuestion(indexNumber);
    } else {
      handleEndGame(); //ends game if index number greater than 9 meaning we're already at the 10th question
    }
    resetOptionBackground();
  }, 1000);
}

//sets options background back to null after display the right/wrong colors
function resetOptionBackground() {
  const options = document.getElementsByName("option");
  options.forEach((option) => {
    document.getElementById(option.labels[0].id).style.backgroundColor = "";
  });
}

// unchecking all radio buttons for next question(can be done with map or foreach loop also)
function unCheckRadioButtons() {
  const options = document.getElementsByName("option");
  for (let i = 0; i < options.length; i++) {
    options[i].checked = false;
  }
}

// function for when all questions being answered
function handleEndGame() {
  let remark = null;
  let remarkColor = null;

  // condition check for player remark and remark color
  if (playerScore <= 3) {
    remark = "Bad Grades, Keep Practicing BABYBOY.";
    remarkColor = "red";
  } else if (playerScore >= 4 && playerScore < 7) {
    remark = "Average Grades, You can do better BABYBOY.";
    remarkColor = "orange";
  } else if (playerScore >= 7) {
    remark = "Excellent, Keep the good work going BABYBOY.";
    remarkColor = "green";
  }
  const playerGrade = (playerScore / 10) * 100;

  //data to display to score board
  document.getElementById("remarks").innerHTML = remark;
  document.getElementById("remarks").style.color = remarkColor;
  document.getElementById("grade-percentage").innerHTML = playerGrade;
  document.getElementById("wrong-answers").innerHTML = wrongAttempt;
  document.getElementById("right-answers").innerHTML = playerScore;
  document.getElementById("score-modal").style.display = "flex";
}

//closes score modal, resets game and reshuffles questions
function closeScoreModal() {
  questionNumber = 1;
  playerScore = 0;
  wrongAttempt = 0;
  indexNumber = 0;
  shuffledQuestions = [];
  NextQuestion(indexNumber);
  document.getElementById("score-modal").style.display = "none";
}

//function to close warning modal
function closeOptionModal() {
  document.getElementById("option-modal").style.display = "none";
}
